MUGA MARK MWANGI

38719 - 00600 NAIROBI, KENYA

20 YEARS | MALE | ID 40461816 | Github Link

+254725406995 | +254754388400 | mwangimuga161@gmail.com

Personality

I am a bright, talented and self-motivated IT specialist who has excellent organizational skills and is highly efficient.

I am a problem solver who looks at problems with a fresh eye and brainstorm on how to find the most suitable solutions for them.

I am driven with the principles of focus on what I want to do and resilience, which helps me, learn new ideas faster.

I am a good team leader and have acquired several leadership skills through being a team player.

I have an extensive experience of assisting in the development and upgrading of database systems and analytical techniques.

Educational Background

2022 – 2022	Cisco Certifications	Certificates	
2021 – 2023	Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture	Diploma in Information Technology	
	and Technology		
2017 – 2020	Kanunga High School	K. C. S. E	С
2013 – 2016	Arch-bishop Gitari Boarding Primary School	K. C. P. E	353

Cisco certifications

- IT Essentials: PC Hardware and Software
- Networking Essentials
- Packet Tracer-Network Essentials Class

Experience

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 Attaché at Ministry of Foreign and Diaspora Affairs.

Key Responsibilities

- Technical ICT support.
- Preventive maintenance of ICT equipment.
- Deployment of ICT equipment to end users.
- Inspection of procured ICT equipment.
- Design of network solutions
- Troubleshooting of printers and scanners.
- Activation and monitoring of LAN.
- Cable trucking and rack maintenance.

June 2022 – Dec 2022 Freelance Developer at Ranqual Consultancies(Intern).

Key Responsibilities

- Assisting in Software Development and maintenance.
- Providing necessary technical system support to Clients.
- Assisting in training potential and existing clients on software functionality.

Sep 2021 – Today IT Clerk

Key Responsibilities

- Basic computer repairs and maintenance.
- Website Development.
- Network maintenance, cable racking and troubleshooting.
- Providing necessary technical system support to users.
- End of year marketing for form one recruitment.

- Digital Marketing.
- Football coaching.
- Website Development. <<u>St.Tito</u>>

Career Objectives

I am looking forward to being accepted into a competitive organization as an employee. This will help me in improving my career path as well us come up with relevant skills that would otherwise be helpful to the organization.

I am good in technical support and administration; I am therefore looking forward to being assigned support and admin roles in a competitive organization to help build up my skills and to be able to explore my passion in programming as a freelancer.

Personal Skills

Problem solving

Analytical

Multitasking

Excellent communication

Team work

Resilience

Integrity at Work

Professional Skills

- Ability to develop creative solutions for complex problems.
- Excellent team worker with strong coaching and mentoring skills.
- Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Database: MySQL, Microsoft Access.
- Software development: Visual Basic (.NET), C#, Java.
- System administration

- Technical support
- Customer service

Achievements and Contributions

- Assisted in installation of internet and Configured inter-device communication at St. Tito Girls High School
- Surveillance Cameras maintenance and support
- Helped develop an Electronic Quality Management System at Ranqual Consulting Group
- Participated in seminars held by **STEM**
- Marketing team at St. Tito Girls High School

Interest and Hobbies

- Sports; Football and Table Tennis
- Drumming
- Voluntary Motivation

Referees

Michael Yego.

Deputy Head ICT and research Division, Ministry of Foreign and Diaspora Affairs, Government of Kenya. P.O. Box 30551, 00100 Nairobi, Kenya.

Tel: +254721368271 myego@mfa.go.ke

Francis Thiongo
Chairperson of Department,
Information Technology Department, Jomo
Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology.
P.O. Box 62000 – 00200 Nairobi, Kenya.
Tel: +254729430727
thiongo@jkuat.ac.ke itdep@icsit.jkuat.ac.ke

Peninah Wanjiku K, Human Resource Manager, St. Tito Girls High School.

P.O. BOX 38719-00600, Nairobi.

Tel: +254722323919

ict@jkuat.ac.ke

st.titohighsch@yahoo.com